Sushant Kr. Rai

UX Designer

www.sushantkumarrai.com sushantkumarrai7@gmail.com +91 85114 50603

I am an India based UX designer and researcher with **6+ years of industry experience**. I help businesses to expand their capacity by connecting their untouched hidden dots because I know how to balance desirability, feasibility and viability lenses to create the most valuable user experiences for products and businesses.

LinkedIn | Behance | Dribbble

Experience

Google / UX Designer

Aug 2022 - Present | Bangalore, India

Currently, I am working with Google Cloud's **Unified Fulfillment Optimization (UFO)** team, whose mission is to efficiently deliver capacity across Alphabet and improve the operational efficiency of Google's data centers.

My responsibilities included leading the UX process for the project, UX research, conducting UX workshops, process strategy, concept design, UI design, prototyping, usability testing, design review, and cross-team collaboration for product development.

Honeywell International / Senior UX Designer

Aug 2019 - Aug 2022 | Bangalore, India

I worked in the Honeywell Connected Enterprise (HCE)-Connected Plant domain, where my responsibilities were to deliver a world-class user experience for the Honeywell Connected Plant (HCP) portfolio.

During my tenure, I've supported **24+ major & minor product releases**, worked on **3 projects** & **10+ new product ideas**, streamlined the UX engagement process for the teams, helped teams achieve **8-figure business** through **15+ customer acquisitions**.

HCL Technologies / Senior UX Designer

Oct 2018 - Aug 2019 | Chennai, India

I Designed a Centralized Data Manager platform for Roche (Hoffmann - La Roche) in order to connect different analyzers (instruments) of the x800 family which consists of Cobas 6800/8800 and STING analyzers. I also conducted user testing sessions to analyze and measure the user experience of a product for **IEC 62366-1** regulatory compliance.

Independent Design Consultant / UX Designer

Feb 2018 - Sep 2018 | Lucknow, India

Worked as an independent design consultant on designing various new media installations, exhibition spaces and web applications for clients.

[24]7.ai, Inc. / Interaction Design Intern (AI & UX/UI)

Jul 2017 - Jan 2018 | Bangalore, India

I Designed an internal communication platform for [24]7.ai chat agents by embedding artificial intelligence(AI) into their enterprise applications to create high-performance cultures that drive organizational success.

Independent Design Consultant / UX Consultant

Jun 2016 - Nov 2016 | Ahmedabad, India

Worked on new product concepts and mobile app design for an Ahmedabad-based industrial IoT company focused on developing and implementing predictive energy and asset intelligence for industries, commercial establishments and utilities.

Education

National Institute of Design (NID) / New Media Design | M.Des.

2015 - 2018 | Gandhinagar, India

I did a Master's in New Media Design, where I explored the possibilities with technologies and worked on experimental projects in different areas of User Experience, Interaction, Art, Architecture and New Media Design to understand the possibilities and relationships between digital and analog mediums.

Government College of Architecture / Bachelor of Architecture (B. Arch)

2010 - 2015 | Lucknow, India

* Batch Topper & Thesis Topper

I did my Bachelor's in Architectural Design, where I worked on various projects of Architecture, Interior Design, Furniture Design and Landscape Design.

Skills

Interaction & Visual Design, UX Research, Design Documentation, System Thinking, Storytelling, Product Development, Data Driven Design, Prototyping, New Media Design, AR/VR, Motion Design, Architectural Design.

Design Thinking & Strategy

Organizing UX Workshops, Experience Mapping, Task Analysis, Information Architecture, Brainstorming, Why/How Laddering, Wireframes, Persons, Paper Prototyping, Scenarios, Storyboarding, Sketching, Contextual Inquiry, Work Model, User Testing, A/B Testing.

Design Tools

Figma, Miro, Sketch, Adobe XD, InVision, Marvel, Adobe CC (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, AfterEffects, PremierPro), Abstract, Balsamiq, Sketch-Up.

Prototyping

Sketching, Processing, Workshop, Model Making, 3d Modelling, 3D Printing, Leaser Cutting, Arduino.